At present, we have an unknown mob
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
Azure Messenger Bomb Threat Incident
First Investigation Meeting
Armed Detective Agency
Conference Room
現在　正体不明の犯罪組織に拠る大規模な市街地爆破予告
threatening to detonate a huge bomb in a crowded area
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
and launch a smear campaign
against the Agency.
及び探偵社への醜聞攻撃が発生しております
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
I know the Agency's in a huge predicament.
探偵社がヤバいっていうのは知ってるさ
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
Tell us about the bomb.
爆弾事件とやらの概略を話しなよ
负
责
人
Maki
This is the message left behind by the perpetrator.
これが現場に残されていた脅迫者の依頼文です
负责人
Maki
I'll read it.
読みます
"Greetings, I hope your
agency is faring well."
謹啓
貴社益々ご繁栄のこととお慶び申し上げます
日
听
小
伍
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
"Forgive my insolence, but I have placed a bomb
却説　僭越ながら　この横浜市内某所に
日听
小伍
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
able to cause mass destruction in a certain location here in Yokohama City."
大容量の殺傷爆弾を設置させていただきました
"To ensure public safety,
つきましては　市井の安全の為
この爆弾を速やかに発見　除去していただきたくご依頼申し上げます
I request that you locate and defuse the bomb at your earliest convenience."
"You have until sundown."
期限は日没
"I have faith in your abilities."
よろしくお願い申し上げます
"Respectfully, the Azure Messenger."
敬白　蒼の使徒
Who could the Azure Messenger be?
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
蒼の使徒なる名に当該とする犯罪者は
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
We have no idea yet.
今のところは不明です
So it's all rigged so that if the bomb detonates,
爆発と同時に解除に失敗した探偵社の醜聞まで
news of the Agency's failure will spread like wildfire.
一斉に広まるって戦法かい
The Agency can withstand sticks and stones,
槍でも大砲でも微風同然の探偵社だが
but this type of attack would severely debilitate us.
この手の攻撃にはどうしたって弱いからね
Since yesterday, the office staff have been searching for plausible locations,
事務方も昨日から候補地を洗い出していますが
but there are too many possibilities.
候補があり過ぎて
Hey.
はい
Are we still unable to reach Rampo-san?
乱歩さんとはまだ連絡がつかないんですか
It seems the case in Kyuushuu
is coming to a head.
九州の事件が佳境のようです
I've requested he contact us as
soon as the criminal is caught, but...
捕まり次第　連絡を貰えるように手配はしてありますが
Any other intel from the taxi driver?
例の運転手からの追加情報は
He denies any knowledge of the bomb.
爆弾については何も知らないと云っています
He wouldn't have the guts to blow up Yokohama itself.
奴に横浜そのものを爆破する度胸はありません
Listen up!
全員聞け
This case is a dastardly act using intel to attack the Armed Detective Agency.
今回の事件は武装探偵社に対する卑劣な情報攻撃である
We have two objectives,
捜査対象は二つ
unveil the Azure Messenger, the instigator,
攻撃者たる蒼の使徒の発見
and defuse the bomb.
そして　爆弾の除去だ
The bomb takes priority due
to its time-limited nature.
優先すべきは時間期限のある爆弾である
If we fail to find the
bomb and lives are lost,
もし発見かなわず人命が失われたなら
we may no longer call ourselves a detective agency.
我らに探偵社を名乗る資格はない
Think of this mission as a struggle for the Agency's existence and pride.
これは武装探偵社の存続と尊厳をかけた戦いであると認識せよ
What time do you think it is, stupid four-eyes?!
何時だと思ってんだ　莫迦眼鏡
You're the only one I know who's still sleeping at 9:00 a.m.
朝の九時に寝てるのはお前くらいだ
Are you able to find the Azure Messenger, the one who sent us that message?
例の依頼書面を出した蒼の使徒は見つかりそうか
Aren't you calling because you wanted to ask me something else?
そんなことより　俺に別件で頼みたいことがあって電話してきたんじゃねぇの
So you know everything.
何でもお見通しってわけか
I only know what I actually know.
知ってることしかわからねぇよ
I want to ask you about tracing the bomb-making equipment.
依頼は爆弾製造の追跡だ
I'll send you the shipping manifest.
購入履歴を送る
A bomb?
爆弾とは　景気がいいなおい
Things are looking up for you.
Cut the chatter and get cracking.
軽口をたたいてないでさっさと始めろ
Oh?
This is to save lives.
これは人命を救う仕事だ
You may be regularly indulging in illicit activities,
いつも非合法なことばかりやっているお前でも　たまには社会の役に立て
but you should serve society sometimes.
Get off your high horse.
偉そうに
You're not my dad.
お前はおいらの父親かよ
No.
違う
Episode 7
Love for the Disease
Called Ideals
I'll never be your father.
俺はお前の父親にはなれん
Are you sure about this?
よろしいのですか
The Agency seemed chaotic due to the bomb threat.
事務所は爆弾騒ぎで大変なご様子ですし
Kunikida-sama seemed occupied, as well.
国木田様もとてもお忙しそうでしたが
Kunikida-kun is a workhorse.
国木田君は仕事の鬼だからねぇ
After all, he spends two hours before going to sleep
何しろ　寝る前に毎日二時間手帳の再確認と追記作業をしているらしいよ
reviewing and editing his notes.
I doubt I could bare that for two minutes.
頭の中に働き蟻でも飼ってる…
Maybe he's got some soldier ants working for him in his brain—
Oh, I didn't know you were here, Kunikida-kun.
なんだ　国木田君いたの
How could you ditch the meeting during an emergency
この緊急時に会議をサボって
and go on a fancy afternoon date?
何を午後の御洒落逢引などしている
Are you jealous of the fancy date?
御洒落逢引羨ましい？
羨ましくないっ
I'm not!
So he is.
羨ましいんだ
She's a victim who was nearly killed.
彼女は犯人に殺されかけた被害者だよ
Ensuring her safety and tending to her psyche
彼女を警護しつつ　心のケアをすることこそ
is an important and urgent duty for the Agency, wouldn't you say?
探偵社として　重要かつ喫緊の任務じゃないか
Why are you, the poster child for sloth and irresponsibility, a good fit for the task?
軽佻浮薄が服を着て歩いているようなお前に出番があるのか
Besides, given her charm,
それに　彼女ほどの美人であれば　恋人くらいいるだろう
I'd assume she has a lover at least.
Apparently, they broke up recently.
聞けばその恋人と少し前に別れたとか
That's why, Kunikida-kun,
だから　国木田君
I say go for it!
いけるよ
いいか　太宰
Listen, Dazai!
I came here because you skipped out on the morning meeting
俺がここに来たのは朝の会議をサボったお前に状況を説明してやる為だ
and I need to tell you what's going on.
I know what's going on.
状況ならわかってるさ
The goal of the Azure Messenger who set the bomb
爆弾を仕掛けた蒼の使徒の目的は
is to crush the Agency.
探偵社潰しだ
Um...
あの…
Are you sure an outsider like me should be hearing this?
このようなお話　部外者の私が聞いてもよいのでしょうか
駄目でしょ
Not really.
佐々城さんは関係者だし　問題ないよ
Sasaki-san's a person of interest in this case.
There's no issue here.
What?
Sasaki-san, what class do you teach at the university again?
佐々城さんが大学で教えてるのって確か…
社会心理学です
Social psychology.
That's great.
それはいい
I'd love to hear what you think about this case.
是非この事件に関するあなたの意見を聞いてみたいね
About the Azure Messenger,
先程から伺っていた蒼の使徒なる人物ですが
it may be related to the Azure King
かの蒼色旗の反乱者事件　蒼王と何か関係があるんじゃないでしょうか
in the notorious Azure Flag Terrorist bombing.
So you think that, as well.
矢張りそう思いますか
It may very well be the Azure King himself.
もしかしたら蒼王本人かもしれません
It's said that he blew himself up after being cornered by the police,
警察に追い詰められ　自爆したということですが
but it's possible he faked his death
或いは死を偽装し　今も生きているのでは？
and is still alive.
This world is incomplete.
この世界は不完全だ
One may grieve or pray,
嘆いても祈っても　偶然で人は死に
but people still die from mishappenings,
and evil goes unpunished to flourish freely in this world.
悪は裁かれず　地上にのさばる
A former official,
元官僚だった蒼王はある時声明と共に政府施設を爆破
the Azure King set off a bomb in a government facility and issued a maxim.
His targets included killers whose cases were dropped due to inadequate prosecutors,
標的は検察のミスで不起訴になった殺人犯や
as well as diet members who were engaged in political corruption on a global scale.
国際的な政治汚職を行った議員など
いずれも法で裁けない凶悪犯ばかりです
All hazardous criminals invulnerable to law.
Thus I shall desire the ideal world.
ならば希求しよう　理想の世界を
It will be built not by the hand of God,
神の御手ではなく
but by our own bloodied fingers.
血塗られた我らの手に拠って
But if the Azure King is alive,
でも　蒼王が生きてるとしたら
why would he attack the Agency like this?
どうして探偵社にこんな攻撃をするんです
I have no idea.
そこまでは
Well, the one who backed the Azure King into a corner
まっ　嘗て蒼王を追い詰めたのは潜窟を突き止めた国木田君だ
is Kunikida-kun, who located his base.
I see.
そうか
Kunikida-kun is the target of vengeance here.
恨まれているのは国木田君か
The terrorist's death was confirmed by the military police after forensic analysis.
あの反乱者の死亡は軍警が現場解析をして出した結論だ
There's no doubting it.
間違いない
Either way,
いずれにしても
you should stay cautious until you figure out who it is.
相手の正体がわかるまでは警戒したほうがいいね
We'll need to hide Sasaki-san somewhere safe, as well.
佐々城さんも安全な処に匿わないと
それは許さんぞ　太宰
That I will not allow, Dazai!
What do you mean?
何のこと？
You think you can keep a lady in your room
護身安全の為と云いくるめ
ご婦人を自分の部屋に囲い
in the name of personal safety?
連日連夜に及んであんなことやこんなことやそんなことまで
And day and night, do such and such unthinkable things?!
Nothing like what you're imagining is happening, though.
君が想像してるようなことは何もないけど
恥を知れ　恥を
Shame on you!
Huh?
When I first let her stay,
だから　初日に泊めた時も隣室で休んだし
I slept in the next room over
当然指一本触れてない
and didn't lay a finger on her, of course.
Well, I knew you misunderstood,
まっ　国木田君が勘違いしてたのは知ってたし
but I thought it was funny so I didn't correct you.
面白いから放置してたけどー
I really wonder why these two are partners.
ほんとにこの二人なんでコンビ組んでんだろう
クソ
Kunikida-kun seems to like Sasaki-san a lot.
国木田君は随分と佐々城さんが気になるみたいだけど
Sasaki-san, what type of man do you like?
佐々城さんはどんな男性が型？
T-Type?
タ…型ですか
It would be presumptuous of me to even have such a thing in mind.
私が男子に型を求めるなど烏滸がましくて大変恐縮ですが
But, I do think it is wonderful when a man strongly believes in an ideal
その　理想に燃え　何かに打ち込む男性などとても素敵だと思います
and pours his heart and soul into it.
That's totally Kunikida-kun.
それ完全に国木田君じゃない
Okay, the two of you can pick up the rest.
じゃあ　後は二人でお話して
こら　太宰
Hey, Dazai!
D-Don't go making assumptions!
か…勝手なこと云うな
Kunikida-kun, you're an open book.
国木田君はわかりやすいな
He really is.
ほんとに
He may be a bit misrepresented,
まあ　少々歪んではいるが
but as you can see, he is an intelligent individual who lives and breathes for his ideals.
見た通り　彼は理想に生きる高徳な人だ
Although, perhaps for that reason, his ideal woman is a bit of a challenge.
その所為か理想の女性も大変なことになってるけど
Care to take a look?
読んでみる？
Bastard, not again! When did you—
貴様また　いつの間に
Give it back!
返せっ
Kunikida-sama...
国木田様
Yes?
ハイ
This goes too far.
これはないです
Kunikida-san's crushed.
国木田さん撃沈
From:  Haruno Kirako
Subject: Received Word from Rampo-san
Atsushi-kun,
We heard back from
Rampo-san!
His case is finished, so
he has time to help us.
Haruno Kirako
We finally heard from Rampo-san.
乱歩さんと連絡が取れたそうです
So we know where the bomb is?
爆弾の場所が判ったんですね
Edogawa Rampo
And here I was hoping to sightsee in Kyuushuu
事件が解決したから　九州観光して温泉玉子でも食べようと思ってたのに
and eat an egg treat since I solved my case.
You all disappoint me.
駄目だね　みんな
You can't conduct a single investigation properly without me.
僕がいないと真面に捜査一つできないんだから
We only have until sundown.
刻限は日没です　場所を教えてください
Please tell us the location.
A department store?
百貨店？　学校？
A school?
それとも駅？
Or a train station?
Any one of these could produce casualties in the hundreds.
どこでも何百人単位の犠牲者が出る
Where's the bomb?
いったいどこに設置されたんだ
The fishing shop.
釣具屋さん
Huh?
The bomb was set in a fishing shop in Negishi.
爆弾は根岸町の釣具屋さんだ
Oh, I see.
そうか　なるほど
You're amazing, Rampo-san.
流石乱歩さんだ
But why a fishing shop?
でも　どうして釣具屋さんなんですか
Do we have a map?
地図ある？
Behind the seat.
座席の後ろだ
Page 97.
九十七頁
Page 97, okay.
九十七頁　九十…
Oh.
The terrorist's target is the petrochemical complex.
犯人の標的は石油コンビナートさ
そうか
I see.
I don't know why I didn't realize it.
何故気づかなかったんだ
Yokohama is one of Japan's major port towns.
日本有数の港湾都市たるこの横浜には
Here, there are many large facilities that store oil and gas.
石油と天然瓦斯を保管する広大な敷地が並んでいる
もし　その石油コンビナート付近で爆発が発生し　槽に引火したら
If an explosion were to ignite nearby storage tanks,
the entire port would be engulfed in flames.
港湾全体が炎に包まれるのは確実だ
However, infiltrating a facility of that nature
だが勿論　石油施設の中に入り込むには
will require getting past pretty good security.
それなりのセキュリティーを突破する必要がある
The easiest approach would be to put a bomb in a car,
一番簡単なのが
車に爆弾を載せて　石油施設の近辺に放置する手管だ
and leave the car near one of the facilities.
So, considering the range of a bomb that can be loaded into a car,
つまり　積載できる爆弾の有効範囲から
that fishing store is the one place that fits the bill.
その条件に合致するのが件の釣具店というわけか
Bingo.
ご名答
The military police's bomb disposal squad has found the bomb,
軍警の爆弾処理班が爆弾を見つけたが
but the bomb can't be moved
due to the timer device.
移動不可能なタイマー式で　日没までの解除は難しいと云ってる
They say it'll be difficult to diffuse it by sundown.
We're having the nearby residents evacuate,
付近の住人を避難させているが　間に合うかどうか
but we're not sure there's enough time.
そんな…
No way.
ただ　停止信号を受信すれば　爆発を止めることができるらしい
However, the bomb's set to deactivate if we can transmit a stop signal.
We have to do something.
なんとかせねば
Wh-What's going on?!
な　何事です
A phone call.
電話だ
Huh?
もしもし
Hello?
Hey, Four-Eyes, is now a good time?
よう眼鏡　今いいか
Rokuzou?
六蔵か
Um...
あの…
どうした
What is it?
I think we're causing a traffic jam.
渋滞の原因になっているような…
Hello?
はい
Hello, Atsushi-kun.
やあ　敦君
Rampo-san?
乱歩さん
Okay.
はい
Hello?
太宰か
Dazai?
President?
社長
Yes.
はい
What?
The military police's...
軍警が？
I see.
なるほど　蛇の道は蛇だな
Set a thief to catch a thief, I see.
I see.
そうですか
That's quite...
それはまた
はい
Okay.
わかった
Understood.
はい
Yes.
ええ
Right.
No, that's helpful.
いや　助かる
Understood.
了解しました
わかりました　社長
Understood, President.
I got a call from Rokuzou.
六蔵からだ
Someone recently ordered a transmitter and other equipment
最近旧国防軍施設に何者かが通信機などを搬入したらしい
to be delivered to a former police facility.
Rampo-san reached a similar conclusion.
乱歩さんの推理も同じです
That settles it, then.
決まりだな
私の電話は社長からだ
My call was from the president.
He was informed by the military
police that the driver has died.
軍警からの連絡で　運転手が死んだ
死んだ？
He's dead?
But I thought he was in the military police's isolation ward for protection.
でも　彼は軍警の隔離施設で保護されてたんじゃないんですか
He died after suddenly collapsing in pain in his cell.
部屋の中で突然苦しみ出して事切れた
No idea how he died,
but the numbers "00" were marked on his palm.
死因は不明だが
掌に「００」という数字の刻印があったそうだよ
Numbers on his palm?
掌に数字だと
What?
なんだ
What in the world's going on?
いったい何が起こってる
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
l
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
Former
Defense
Force
Facility
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
T-20
Minutes
Until
Detonation
Kunikida-kun!
国木田君
Doppo Poet!
「独歩吟客」
「閃光榴弾」
Flash Bang!
We're at the right place!
ここで間違いないようだ
You two, go upstairs!
二人は二階へ
Find the transmitter and send the stop signal!
通信機を探して　停止信号を送るんだ
What the...
なんだ
Give me your number.
君の数字をおくれよ
How've you been?
元気？
You're looking great.
元気で素敵だよ君
I'm sure you have a great number.
さぞかしいい数字を持っているんだろうね
This is...
これは…
You sniffed out the place just like your reputation predicted.
ここを嗅ぎつけるなんて　評判通りだー
The Armed Detective Agency's impressive.
流石武装探偵社だなー
Very impressive.
流石武装探偵社だ
The sun's setting.
夕日が沈む
Can you figure it out?
操作できます？
It's easy!
簡単だ
But I can't do it.
でも私には無理
What?
You have to insert the release key here and turn it,
ここに解除鍵を差し込んで回すだけだけど
but I don't have it.
私はそれを持ってない
どうするんです
What are we going to do?!
What are you doing here?
何をしている
Wow, we've got quite a super heavy hitter here!
スーパーヘビー級だねこりゃあ
This one's ability can perform remote attacks!
こいつ　遠距離攻撃の異能力者か
What's your number now?
君の数字はいくつになった
Number?
数字？
My ability cannot be evaded, you see.
僕の力はね　避けられないんだ
I can send people who have numbers
僕は数字のある人間を好きな方向に吹き飛ばせるのさ
in any direction I want.
Even if they're on the
other side of the earth.
仮令地球の裏側にいてもね
And once their number becomes zero,
そして　その数字がゼロになった時
they'll die in agony.
苦しみもがいて死ぬ
No one can escape that fate.
その運命からは逃れられない
No one.
誰も　誰も　誰も
Are you the boss of this group?
お前が…頭領か
Your group poses a greater obstacle than the Mafia, for sure.
確かに君達はマフィアより厄介だ
But the Armed Detective
Agency is now finished.
だがその武装探偵社ももう終わりさ
Here's the key.
ここに鍵がある
爆発を止める解除鍵だよ
It's the release key to stop the bomb.
Without it, you can't stop the bomb.
これがなければ爆弾は止められない
Do you want it?
欲しいかい
Of course you do.
欲しいよねー
If you want it... here.
ほしいなら　こうだ
Now, there is no hope.
これで希望は潰えた
It's finished.
もう終わりだ　終わりだよね
It's over, isn't it?
You fool!
この阿呆が
Atsushi-kun!
敦君
You have really strong arms.
君凄い腕力だねー
You should have gone into the bouncer business.
荷運び業者のほうが向いてるよ
Kunikida-kun!
国木田君
I know!
わかっとるわ
Don't think you can pull the same trick twice!
何度も同じこと
Dazai!
太宰
Here!
はいよ
Will you be the next one to give me a number?
今度は君が数字をくれるのかい
Impossible!
莫迦な　何故数字が刻印されない
Why has no number marked you?!
Unfortunately, your ability will no longer have any effect.
残念ながら君の異能力はもう効かない
Also, you should really have your partner switch careers and be a bouncer.
それと
相棒は荷運びに転職させたほうが…
The weight difference doesn't seem to faze him at all.
体重差関係なし
Dazai-san.
太宰さん
Their partnership is amazing.
このコンビ凄い
Oh, right!
そうだ
Kunikida-san, the key?
国木田さん　鍵は？
He broke it.
奴が壊した
What?!
Then what about the bomb?
じゃあ爆弾はどうなるんですか
We don't have time—
時間がもう…
落ち着け　小僧
Calm down, brat.
Doppo Poet.
「独歩吟客」
「解除鍵」
Release key.
My ability allows me to recreate anything I have laid eyes on
俺の異能力は俺が一度この目で見て
and understood its form and function.
その形と機能を理解した物を再現できる
However, the object's size is limited to that of a pocketbook.
ただし
大きさはおよそ手帳のサイズに限るがな
So your notebook is really a tool that brings your ideals into reality.
国木田さんの手帳は本当に国木田さんの理想を実現するツールなんですね
You're visiting the graves of those who have lost their lives?
犠牲になった方のお墓参りですか
Yes.
ああ
When I first caused casualties during a job,
初めて業務で死者を出した時には
I cried so much I couldn't get up,
起き上がれぬ程泣き　無断欠勤した
and I didn't go to work at times.
But now, I don't even shed a tear.
だが今では涙一つ出ん
I just choose to visit their graves in exchange, or that's how I think of it.
故にその代替として　こうして墓参りすべきだとそう思っている
Will the dead by comforted by tears?
涙を流せば　死んだ人は浮かばれますか
I doubt they'd be comforted or redeemed by tears.
おそらく浮かばれも救われもせんだろう
After all, their time stopped at the moment of their deaths.
何故なら　彼らの時間は既に止まっている
I confess I told a lie earlier.
先般のお話で私一つ嘘をつきました
My significant other and I parted ways because he died.
別れた恋人とは死別したのです
そうか
I see.
What you said is true.
仰る通りです
Time no longer has meaning for the dead.
死んだ人の時間はもう止まっていて
No matter what I may do for him,
今から何をしても　かの人は喜ばず
he cannot rejoice in it,
nor smile because of it.
微笑みません
I lost my composure without meaning to.
つい取り乱しました
I have something I must attend to.
所用がございますので　これで
Excuse me.
Goodbye.
さよなら
Hello.
もしもし
Kunikida-kun?
国木田君　ちょっと来てほしいのだけど
I need you for something.
What do you want here, of all places?
こんな場所で何の用だ
What do you think this is?
これ　なんだと思う
It's a survey of Yokohama we found on a computer in their base.
潜窟のパソコンの中にあった横浜の調査情報だよ
Surprisingly, it concludes that eradicating the Agency is the first priority
驚くことに　この横浜支配には探偵社の殲滅が第一だと書かれていた
in order to take control of Yokohama.
And not the Port Mafia, who control the underworld?
裏社会を牛耳るポートマフィアではなくか
They were being manipulated by false intel.
彼らは踊らされていたんだ
偽の情報でね
So there's another mastermind?
まだ黒幕か
Actually, I've sent an email to the one I believe is truly behind this.
実は真犯人と思っている人物に書面を出した
I said I have proof that they are the one truly responsible.
犯人である証拠を持っているとね
That person should be here any moment now.
もうすぐここに来る筈だよ
It can't be you!
まさかお前が…
You're the one, Rokuzou?!
お前がそうなのか　六蔵
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだお前
So it hasn't started yet?
まだ始まってねえのかよ
I see.
そうか　君は私の電子書面をハッキングで覗き見たね
You took a peek at my email by hacking into my account, didn't you?
So it's not really you!
本当にお前じゃないんだな
俺はただ真犯人の顔を拝みたかっただけだよ
I just wanted to take a look at the
one who's actually responsible.
So it's really, really not you, right—
本当に本当だな　お前じゃ…
Look out!
退いて眼鏡
So you're the Azure Messenger,
矢張りあなたが蒼の使徒か
Sasaki Nobuko-san.
佐々城信子さん
It can't be.
そんな
I doubt this is the first time you used your intelligence
思うに　あなたがその頭脳を犯罪に使うのは初めてじゃないね
to execute a crime, either.
He was a man who lived for his ideals.
あの人は理想に燃えた人でした
純粋に犯罪のない世界を望み　それ故に自分の手を血に染めました
He was pure in his intentions to seek out the world of crime,
and that is why he got blood on his hands.
I just wanted to grant his desire and make his ideals come true.
私はどうにかその理想を叶えてあげたかった
Your significant other, the Azure King,
あたなの恋人　蒼王は
was an idealist who wanted to prosecute criminals who could not be judged by law
法では裁けない犯罪者を犯罪に拠って断罪する理想主義者だった
through illegal means.
This incident was meant to carry on his work.
今回の事件はその続きだ
Lower your gun!
銃を下ろせ　こんなことをして何になる
What good will this accomplish?
Don't you understand?
おわかりになりませんか
You resemble him in a way.
あなたはどこかあの人に似ています
Your plan was very sophisticated.
あなたの計画は実にスマートだ
Without committing a single crime of your own,
自らは何も罪を犯さず　探偵社を貶め　誘拐犯と犯罪組織を滅ぼしてみせた
you set up the Agency to take the fall,
and you destroyed both the kidnapper and the criminal organization behind him.
But you yourself have no convictions nor ideals.
けどあなた自身には　何の信念も理想もない
You're just being swept along by the flow.
ただ流されていただけだ
I'm just tired, now.
もう疲れました
I want to be free from all this.
私は解き放たれたいのです
Will you shoot me, Dazai-san?
私を撃ちますか　太宰さん
But I've lowered my gun.
でも私は銃を下ろしました
If you were to shoot me now,
この状況で私を撃つと　過剰防衛になりますね
it'd be excessive use of force.
Kunikida-san's watching us.
国木田さんが見ています
You're right.
そう　私には撃てない
I can't shoot.
However...
でも…
The Azure King killed my dad.
蒼王は父上の敵だ
Good riddance.
…態ぁ見やがれ
Why?!
何故だ
Why does it have to end this way?!
何故こんなことになる
What went wrong?!
何が間違いだった
Who was wrong?!
誰が悪かった
No one was wrong.
誰も悪くない
This was the only possible outcome.
この結果しか有り得なかったんだ
Shut up!
黙れ
You could've saved her!
お前なら救えた筈だ
Are you saying this is justice?!
これが正しい結果だとでも云うのか
Justice is a weapon.
正しさとは武器だ
It can be used to cause harm,
それは傷つけることはできても　守り救済することはできない
but it cannot protect or save others.
What killed Sasaki-san was, in the end, the justice of the Azure King
佐々城さんを殺したのは　結局蒼王の
and of you.
そして君の正しさだ
Kunikida-kun,
国木田君
as long as you pursue your ideals,
君がその理想を求める限り　いつか蒼王の炎が君にも宿るだろう
the flames that burned in the Azure King will one day take root in you
and raze everything around you.
そして周囲ごと焼き尽くす
Still!
それでも
I'll still push on until I push past it!
それでも進んで突き抜けてやる
Don't underestimate my ideals!
俺の理想をなめるなよ
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
boku ga boku de irareru
I was searching for the reason
riyuu o sagashiteita
why I'm able to stay as I am.
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
anata no mune no naka de
If there's a version of me
ikiteiru boku ga iru no naraba
that exists in your heart,
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
kurayami mo nagai sakamichi mo
Then even if darkness looms on this rocky road,
koeteikeru you na boku ni nareru hazu
I'll be able to find the way to the new me.
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
sorezore ni ima o aruiteru bokura ga waraeru you ni
So that we can keep smiling in our own moments,
ikiteiru imi o tashikameainagara susumeru you ni
So that we can explore the meaning of life together,
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
あなたがあなたでいれるように
anata ga anata de ireru you ni
So that you can stay how you are.
kanashimi ni kurete anata no namida ga koboreru toki
Whenever you're overcome by grief, and tears flow,
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
samishisa ni afureta kokoro ga shibondeku toki
Whenever your heart floods with loneliness and you waste away,
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに
boku no namae o yondekureta mitai ni
Just as you once called out mine.
Atsushi, aren't you hurt?
敦　どっか怪我していないかい
No, not in the slightest.
いいえ　全然全く　頗る健康です
I'm in good health.
Oh, how boring.
なんだぃ　つまんないね
Um, about your "treatment," Dr. Yosano.
あの　与謝野先生の治療って具体的には何をするんですか
How does it work, exactly?
知りたいかい
Would you like to find out?
前に治療を受けた谷崎辺りに聞いてみな
Why don't you ask Tanizaki since he was treated by me before?
いや　でも谷崎さん怯えて震えるばかりで何も教えてくれないんですけど
Oh, but Tanizaki-san just shivers in fear
and won't tell me anything.
Next time on Bungou Stray Dogs, Episode 8:
次回　「文豪ストレイドッグス」第八話
Teaching Them To Kill; Then To Die.
「人を殺して死ねよとて」
Episode 8
Teaching Them To Kill; Then to Die
異能力 「君死給勿」
Ability: Thou Shalt Not Die.